In June of 1998,
في يونيو 1998،
Tori Murden McClure left Nags Head, North Carolina for France.
غادرت توري ماردن مكلار "ناكز هد"، كارولاينا الشمالية إلى فرنسا.
That's her boat, the American Pearl.
ذلك هو قاربها، اللؤلؤة الأمريكية.
It's 23 feet long and just six feet across
طوله 23 قدم
The deck was the size of a cargo bed of a Ford F-150 pickup truck.
كان ظهر المركب يساوي سرير شحن عربة فورد F-150 الصغيرة
Tori and her friends built it by hand,
توري و أصدقاؤها بنوه بأيديهم،
and it weighed about 1,800 pounds.
وكان وزنه حوالي 1800 باوند.
Her plan was to row it alone
خطتها هي أن تجذف لوحدها
across the Atlantic Ocean --
عبر المحيط الأطلسي.
no motor, no sail --
بدون محرك، بدون شراع --
something no woman and no American had ever done before.
لم تقم امرأة ولا أمريكي بشيء كهذا قط.
This would be her route:
هذا هو خط سيرها:
over 3,600 miles across the open North Atlantic Ocean.
أكثر من 3600 ميل عبر المحيط الأطلسي الشمالي المفتوح.
Professionally, Tori worked as a project administrator
مهنيًا، تعمل توري كمديرة مشاريع
for the city of Louisville, Kentucky,
لبلدية لويفيل في كنتاكي،
her hometown,
مسقط رأسها،
but her real passion was exploring.
لكن شغفها هو الاستكشاف.
This was not her first big expedition.
هذه ليست رحلتها الاستكشافية الأولى.
Several years earlier, she'd become the first woman to ski to the South Pole.
قبل عدة سنوات، أصبحت أول امرأة تتزلج إلى القطب الجنوبي.
She was an accomplished rower in college,
كانت مجذفة محترفة في الجامعة،
even competed for a spot on the 1992 U.S. Olympic team,
وحتى نافست من أجل مكان لها في المنتخب الأولومبي عام 1992،
but this, this was different.
لكن هذا، هذا كان تحد مختلف.
(Video) (Music) Tori Murden McClure: Hi. It's Sunday, July 5.
(فيديو) (موسيقى) توري مردن مكلير: أهلًا، اليوم الأحد 5 يوليو.
Sector time 9 a.m.
إنها الـ 9 صباحًا حسب التوقيت المحلي.
So that's Kentucky time now.
وهذا هو الوقت في كنتاكي الآن.
Dawn Landes: Tori made these videos as she rowed.
دان لاندز: سجلت توري هذه الفيديوهات بينما كانت تجذف.
This is her 21st day at sea.
هذا هو يومها 21 في البحر.
At this point, she'd covered over 1,000 miles,
حتى هذه النقطة، قطعت أكثر من 1000 ميل،
had had no radio contact in more than two weeks
لم تستطع الاتصال لاسلكيًا لأكثر من أسبوعين
following a storm that disabled all her long-range communications systems
بعد أن أفسدت العاصفة كل أنظمة الاتصال بعيدة المدى خاصتها
just five days in.
لخمسة أيام فقط.
Most days looked like this.
كانت أغلب الأيام هكذا.
At this point, she'd rowed over 200,000 strokes,
حتى هذه النقطة، قامت بأكثر من 200000 تجذيفة،
fighting the current and the wind.
تتصارع مع التيار والرياح.
Some days, she traveled as little as 15 feet.
وفي بعض الأيام، تقطع أقل من 15 قدم.
Yeah.
نعم.
And as frustrating as those days were,
بقدر ما كانت تلك الأيام محبطة،
other days were like this.
كانت أيام أخرى هكذا.
(Video) TMM: And I want to show you my little friends.
(فيديو) ت. م. م. : سأريكم أصدقائي الصغار.
DL: She saw fish, dolphins,
د. ل. : لقد رأت سمك، دلافين،
whales, sharks,
حيتان، قروش،
and even some sea turtles.
و حتى بعض سلاحف البحر.
After two weeks with no human contact,
بعد أسبوعين من انقطاع الاتصال،
Tori was able to contact a local cargo ship
استطاعت توري أن تتصل بسفينة محلية للشحن
via VHF radio.
باستخدام الأمواج عالية التردد.
(Video) TMM: Do you guys have a weather report, over?
(فيديو) ت. م. م.: هل لديكم تقرير الطقس، انتهى؟
Man: Heading up to a low
بحار: نتجه إلى انخفاض
ahead of you but it's heading,
أمامك لكنه يبتعد،
and you're obviously going northeast
وأنت على ما يبدو تتجهين جهة الشمال الشرقي
and there's a high behind us.
وهناك ارتفاع خلفنا.
That'd be coming
وسيكون قادمًا
east-northeast also.
من جهة الشرق والشمال الشرقي أيضًا.
TMM: Good.
د. م. م.: جيد.
DL: She's pretty happy to talk to another human at this point.
د. ل.: كانت سعيدة بالتحدث مع شخص آخر لحد الآن.
(Video) TMM: So weather report says nothing dramatic
(فيديو) ت. م. م.: إذًا لم يذكر تقرير الطقس أن
is going to happen soon.
أي شيء درامي سيحدث قريبًا.
DL: What the weather report didn't tell her
د. ل.: ما لم يذكره تقرير الطقس
was that she was rowing right into the path of Hurricane Danielle
أنها كانت تتجه مباشرة إلى مسار الإعصار دانييل
in the worst hurricane season on record in the North Atlantic.
في أسوأ موسم أعاصير مسجل في الأطلس الشمالي.
(Video) TMM: Just sprained my ankle.
(فيديو) ت. م. م.: لقد لويت كاحلي للتو.
There's a very strong wind from the east now.
هناك رياح قوية من الشرق الآن.
It's blowing about.
إنها تعصف.
After 12 days of storm
بعد 12 يوم من العاصفة
I get to row for four hours
استطعت أن أجذف لأربع ساعات
without a flagging wind.
من دون حتى رياح ضعيفة.
I'm not very happy right now.
لست سعيدة جدًا الآن.
As happy as I was this morning,
بقدر ما كنت سعيدة هذا الصباح،
I am unhappy now, so ...
أنا تعيسة الآن، إذًا ...
DL: After nearly three months at sea,
د. ل.: بعد قرابة 3 أشهر في البحر،
she'd covered over 3,000 miles.
قطعت 3000 ميل.
She was two thirds of the way there,
بقى لها الثلثين من الرحلة،
but in the storm, the waves were the size of a seven-story building.
لكن في العاصفة، كانت الأمواج بطول مبنى 7 طوابق.
Her boat kept capsizing.
استمر المركب في الانقلاب.
Some of them were pitchpole capsizes, flipping her end over end,
كان بعض الانقلاب رأسيًا. نعم. رأسًا على عقب.
and rowing became impossible.
وأصبح التجذيف مستحيلًا.
(Video) TMM: It's 6:30 a.m.
(فيديو) ت. م. م.: إنها 6:30 صباحًا.
I'm in something big, bad and ugly.
أنا في شيء كبير وسيئ وقبيح.
Two capsizes.
انقلابين.
Last capsize, I took the rib off the top of my ceiling with my back.
في الانقلاب الأخير، نزعت الضلع من أعلى السقف بظهري.
I've had about six capsizes now.
انقلبت 6 مرات لحد الآن.
The last one was a pitchpole.
آخر مرة انقلبت رأسًا على عقب.
I have the Argus beacon with me.
كان رقيب المنارة معي.
I would set off the distress signal,
أرسلت إشارة استغاثة،
but quite frankly, I don't think they'd ever be able to find this little boat.
لكن صراحة لا أعتقد أنهم سيجدون هذا المركب الصغير.
It's so far underwater right now,
إنه بعيد تحت الماء الآن،
the only part that's showing pretty much is the cabin.
الجزء الوحيد المرئي هو القمرة.
It's about 10 a.m.
إنها 10 صباحًا.
I've lost track of the number of capsizes.
لم أعد أعرف كم مرة انقلبت.
I seem to capsize about every 15 minutes.
يبدو أنني أنقلب كل 15 دقيقة تقريبًا.
I think I may have broken my left arm.
أعتقد أنني كسرت ذراعي اليسرى.
The waves
وقطّعت الأمواج
are tearing the boat to shreds.
المركب إربًا إربًا.
I keep praying because
سأستمر في الصلاة لأنني
I'm not sure I'm going to make it through this.
لست متأكدة أنني سأخرج من هذا المأزق.
DL: Tori set off her distress beacon
د. ل.: أشعلت توري منارة الاستغاثة
and was rescued by a passing container ship.
و قد أُنقذت عن طريق سفينة لنقل الحاويات.
They found her abandoned boat two months later adrift near France.
وجدوا قاربها المهجور بعد شهرين طافيًا قرب فرنسا.
I read about it in the newspaper.
قرأتُ عن القصة في جريدة.
In 1998, I was a high school student living in Louisville, Kentucky.
في 1998، كنت طالبة في الثانوي في لويفيل، كنتاكي.
Now, I live in New York City. I'm a songwriter.
الآن أعيش في نيويورك سيتي. أنا كاتبة أغاني.
And her bravery stuck with me, and I'm adapting her story
شجاعتها بقت معي، وحولت قصتها
into a musical called "Row."
إلى قصة موسيقية تدعى "جذِّفي."
When Tori returned home,
عندما عادت توري إلى المنزل،
she was feeling disheartened,
كانت تشعر بالإحباط،
she was broke.
كانت مكسورة.
She was having a hard time making the transition
كانت تعاني في العودة
back into civilization.
إلى الحضارة.
In this scene, she sits at home.
في هذا المشهد، تجلس في المنزل.
The phone is ringing, her friends are calling,
يرن الهاتف، يتصل الأصدقاء،
but she doesn't know how to talk to them.
لكنها لا تعرف كيف ترد عليهم.
She sings this song. It's called "Dear Heart."
فتغني هذه الأغنية، بعنوان "قلبي العزيز".
(Guitar)
(عزف)
When I was dreaming,
عندما كنت أحلم،
I took my body
أخذت جسمي
to beautiful places
إلى أماكن جميلة
I'd never been.
لم أزرها.
I saw Gibraltar,
رأيت جبل طارق،
and stars of Kentucky
ونجوم كنتاكي
burned in the moonlight,
تشتعل في ضوء القمر،
making me smile.
تجعلني أبتسم.
And when I awoke here,
وعندما استيقظت هنا،
the sky was so cloudy.
كانت السماء ملبدة بالغيوم.
I walked to a party
ذهبت إلى حفلة
where people I know
حيث الذين أعرف
try hard to know me
يصعب عليهم معرفتي
and ask where I've been,
ويسألون أين كنت،
but I can't explain
لكن لا يمكن أن أشرح
what I've seen to them.
لهم ما رأيت.
Ah, listen, dear heart.
آه، أنصت، قلبي العزيز.
Just pay attention,
انتبه فقط،
go right from the start.
ابدأ من البداية.
Ah, listen, dear heart.
آه، أنصت، قلبي العزيز.
You can fall off the map,
يمكن أن تقع من على الخريطة
but don't fall apart.
لكن لا تنهار.
Ooh ooh ooh,
أوه أوه أوه،
ah ah ah ah ah.
آه آه آه آه آه،
Ah ah,
آه آه،
ah ah ah.
آه آه آه.
When I was out there,
عندما كنت هناك،
the ocean would hold me,
كان يشدني المحيط،
rock me and throw me,
يأرجحني ويقذفني،
light as a child.
كطفل صغير.
But now I'm so heavy,
لكني الآن ثقيلة جدًا،
nothing consoles me.
ولا شيء يواسيني.
My mind floats like driftwood,
تفكيري كخشبة تطفو،
wayward and wild.
إلى الأمام وبشدة.
Ah, listen, dear heart.
آه، أنصت، قلبي العزيز.
Just pay attention,
انتبه فقط،
go right from the start.
ابدأ من البداية.
Ah, listen, dear heart.
آه، أنصت، قلبي العزيز.
You can fall off the map,
يمكن أن تقع من على الخريطة
but don't fall apart.
لكن لا تنهار.
Ooh.
أوه.
Eventually, Tori starts to get her feet under her.
أخيرًا، بدأت توري في التعافي.
She starts hanging out with her friends again.
وبدأت في الالتقاء بأصدقائها مرة أخرى.
She meets a guy and falls in love for the first time.
التقت برجل ووقعت في الحب للمرة الأولى.
She gets a new job working for another Louisville native,
حصلت على عمل مع أحد سكان لويفيل،
Muhammad Ali.
محمد علي.
One day, at lunch with her new boss,
في يوم ما، وهي تتغدى مع مديرها الجديد،
Tori shares the news that two other women
شاركت توري الأخبار أن امرأتين غيرها
are setting out to row across the mid-Atlantic,
بدأن التجذيف عبر منتصف المحيط،
to do something that she almost died trying to do.
لفعل شيء كادت أن تموت وهي تحاول فعله.
His response was classic Ali:
كان جواب علي كلاسيكيًا:
"You don't want to go through life
"لا تريدين أن تخوضي الحياة
as the woman who almost rowed across the ocean."
كالمرأة التي كادت أن تجذف عبر المحيط. "
He was right.
كان على حق.
Tori rebuilt the American Pearl,
أعادت توري بناء اللؤلؤة الأمريكية،
and in December of 1999,
وفي ديسمبر 1999،
she did it.
فعلتها.
(Applause) (Guitar)
(تصفيق) (عزف)
Thank you.
شكرًا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)